Neva Bupa has launched Reshore 3.0
plan.  Before this, Roses 2.0 plan
proved to be their blockbuster plan.  But is this
sequel plan really better than Ratio 2.0
or just a fancy upgrade?
Its
unlimited sum insured feature is creating the most buzz.  This means that there will
no longer be any limit on your treatment expenses.
But will such features be useful to you
?  There are a total of four variants under Ratio 3.0.
In today's video, we will understand the exact difference between these four variants so that you can decide
which is the best variant for you.  The
company has also provided add-on options
through which
we will also know how much you can modify your plan.  And the
biggest question is that the company has given unlimited sum insured.
What impact has this had on the premium of the policy i.e. its price
?  Is the policy premium reasonable
or will the company charge too much?   That
means in today's video we will understand Neemupper Read
3.0 plan very closely.
Features, benefits, add-ons, variants as well as pricing of this plan.
And the matter will
not end here.  At the end of the video,
I will also tell you what my honest, unbiased opinion is about this plan.
So if you are confused whether
you should take Reshore 3.0 plan or not,
then you must watch today's video till the end
because you may get to know some things about this plan
which
you might not have heard till now.  So what are you waiting for
?  Let's quickly start this video.  There
are a total of four variants within the Reshor 3.0 plan.  This is the most base variant.  The smaller
variant is the Classic.  Above that comes
Select.  After that, Elite and the top variant
is Black.  The two variants below
are Classic and Select.
You will find some cappings and sub limits within these two variants.
But the company has provided
more coverage in the two variants mentioned above.
If you want to take Ratio 3.0 plan
as an adult, then your age should be
between 18 years to 99 years.
And if you want to include dependent children
in your policy, that is, those children
who are not yet married and are
not earning anything, then they can
remain in this policy from the age of 91 days to 30 years.
You can choose between individual and family floater
options.
A family floater plan can be taken for a maximum of six members.
If we talk about sum
insured, here the company has given the option of minimum ₹5 lakh, maximum
₹1 lakh and unlimited sum insured.
You will get only three options.
If you choose unlimited sum insured, there will be no
limit on your medical expenses.  And if you
want to take a fixed sum insurance then you have only two
options.  ₹ lakh and ₹1 lakh.  If we talk about
tenure, here
you can buy a long term policy of maximum 5 years.
If you take a two-year policy together,
you will get a 10% discount on the second year's premium.  If you take a 3-year
policy, you will get a 10% discount on the second year and
12.5% ​​discount on the third year.  If you
take a four-year policy,
you will get a 12.5% ​​discount on the fourth year premium as well. If you
take a five-year policy, you will
get a 12.5% ​​discount on the fifth year premium as well.   The
eligibility conditions are the same for all four variants.
But now the question arises,
what is the difference between the variants?  So for that
we have to understand the coverage and benefits
in detail.  The first point is room
rent and this is where there
is a difference between the four variants.  If you have the base
variant, the classic variant, then you can get the
treatment done inside the general board or general room.
If you have the Select
variant, you can get a twin sharing room.  That
means two patients in one room.
If you have the Elite variant, you can choose
any room category except deluxe and suite rooms.
And if you have the
top variant that is Black then there is
no limit on room rent.  If you exceed the
room rent category mentioned in your variant and
take a category above it,
then money will be deducted from the total claim amount.  The
details of how much it will be cut are
visible to you on the screen right now.   The
left side is your variant.  After that there
is your room category and on the right side
you can see the copayment percentage.
Similarly, there is a difference in road and air ambulance
coverage across the four variants.
If you have the lower two variants
i.e. Classic and Select, then
you can claim for road ambulance hospitalization at ₹2000.
And there is
no capping or submission on the two variants above.
Talking about air ambulance, there
is no air ambulance coverage in the lower two variants.  In the top two variants i.e. Elite
and Black, you also get air ambulance coverage up to ₹5 lakh.
In the Reshore 3.0 plan, the company says that even if you are
hospitalized for 2 hours,
we will give you the claim and along with this, AYUSH
coverage is also provided.  But in that, 24
hours in-patient hospitalization
is necessary.  Modern treatments are a
very important part of every policy as the treatments
are expensive and most of the hospitals are
adopting these latest procedures.  So
if you have the lower two variants that is
Classic and Select then there is a subvention of ₹1 lakh.  That
means
you cannot claim more than ₹1 lakh for modern treatment.
But if there are top two variants then that
is Alt and Black.  So there
is no sublimit on this.  Up to some insured
modern treatments will be covered.   The
next benefit is Booster Plus benefit
which is a very popular benefit
in NIBA plans.  If you do not use any sum insured,
it will be carried forward to the next year
and its maximum
limit is 10 times of sum insured.  There
is a policy of ₹1 lakh.  You
can collect Booster Plus benefits up to 10 times that.   This
means that a policy worth ₹1 lakh can become worth ₹1 crore 10 lakh
with the addition of this Booster Plus
benefit.  But you will get this only in sum insured of Rs 5 and 10 lakh
because if it
is unlimited sum insured then there is
no need for such feature in it.  The next
benefit is the restoration benefit called
Reshore Forever.  If your policy is for ₹5 and
₹1 lakh and any first claim
comes under the policy then this Reshore Forever
benefit gets triggered.  And then you can use
this money for any treatment up to 100% of the sum insured for life time.
If you have taken unlimited sum insured
then this benefit is not applicable
because there is already no limit on the sum insured, hence
it will be of
no use.  If we talk about the
number of days of pre and post hospitalization, then this plan will cover the
expenses of 60 days before admission and
180 days post hospitalization expenses after discharge.
Those should be expenses related to this treatment.  There are
expenses for seeing a doctor,
medicines, diagnostic tests.
You
can claim these expenses from the company as a reimbursement claim.
You can get treatment at home in both the categories of Home Care Treatment and Domiciliary Treatment.  But
some terms and conditions
are applicable in both.  But
you will get coverage for both of these in all four variants of Reshore 3.0 plan
and that too covered up to the sum
insured.  Similarly, organ donor
charges are also covered up to the sum insured.
If a policyholder needs to undergo an organ
transplant, the
Resure 3.0 plan will also cover those expenses
without any supplements.
Lock the Clock has been one of the most popular features of Neema Bupa health insurance plans.  That means,
if I buy a health insurance policy today at the age of 25, then
until the claim comes,
I will keep paying the premium at the same age.   There will be
no premium for the slab with edge.
So the lower two variants,
Classic and Select, do not have the lock the
clock feature.  But
you will get this benefit in the top variants i.e. Elite and Black.
Apart from this, in all these four
variants you can cover PED from the first day.
Subject to loadings.   This
means that the insurance company can take some extra money from you and
provide coverage for your existing illness from the very first day.  But
it will be subject to underwriter approval.   If
it is a serious disease or the risk
is very high then approval may not be granted.  But
if you have mild PD and
want coverage from day one, then by paying a little extra money
you can get coverage from day one.   The
next feature is the surprise benefit.  The company
says it has taken the Ratio 3.0 plan.  Now
download the NVP app on your mobile.  You will
get some surprise.  What
could be the surprise?  Is.  There may be some value added services.
Some online service companies may
provide it to you free of cost.  And the final
benefit of the base standard plan is second
medical opinion.  You can get unlimited second medical opinions from Neva Bupa's panel of
doctors.  If
you have been diagnosed with a disease and wish to seek treatment,
you
can seek consultation or advice from in-network
facilities and doctors.  Now till here
friends you understood the standard coverage of Reshor 3.0
and we
also understood the differences between the four variants.  Now I am going to tell you about some very
important add-ons through which
you can completely transform the coverage of your plan.  You
can modify the plan at all costs.  And it
also has some new add-ons which
you will not get in the old Neevapa plans.  The
first add-on is Neevapa One, which is a
membership that the company offers you.
If you take NVBA One membership,
you will be given priority in your claims.
Whatever issues you have will be
addressed quickly and apart from that, you can also avail the facility of some
value added services like annual health
checkups.
We will check the price of this membership
in the pricing section.   The
second add-on is Cashback Plus.  If you do
not have any claim in the first year, then
10% of your premium will
come into your wallet.  Suppose my premium was
₹200,000 without GST, then 10% of it i.e. ₹2000 will be
added to my wallet.  If there is no claim next year also, then
5% will be added.   If it does
n't come next year also then 5% will be added.
And you will
also get 10% extra on a block of 3 years.  How can I use this money, these
rewards that are inside the wallet
?  I
can pay any deductible amount or
pay my policy premium.   I can
give it for comment.  I can use
these reward points for OPD expenses.
But you will have to take the add-on
Cashback Plus.  The next add on is Heads
Up.  This is also a brand new add on.
In this, the company says that if there is any planned
hospitalization then
you should call us 48 hours in advance.  We will tell you
in which hospital you have to take treatment, you
can get it at 15% discount on premium
if you take this add-on while purchasing the policy.
But if you do not do this,
in case of emergency you have to call within 24 hours of being admitted.
If
you take treatment outside without confirming by calling in this manner,
then you will have to pay a comment of 20%.  The
second add on is the tiered network.
You already know this.
In a tiered network, the company will give you a
list of hospitals in the beginning.  If
treatment is done in these hospitals, full
claim will be given.  If treatment is done outside these, there will be a
co-payment of 20%.  You will
get a discount of 15% on the policy premium.  So such
add-ons greatly restrict your freedom of choice.  They
impose a lot of restrictions on him.  So I don't think
anyone should buy these add ons.
Even if you have a policy, you do not have the freedom of
choice as to which hospital you want to get
treatment in.  In the next two addons, you can
reduce the waiting period for your specific diseases and pre-existing diseases.   The
waiting period for specific diseases is 24
months. You
can extend it to 12 months or even 36 months, and
you will get a discount.  For those who have
PED (pre-existing disease), are already suffering from any disease, are
undergoing treatment, are taking medicines,
you can reduce its kidney period from 36 months to 24
months or even 12 months.
Next and one is copayment.  If you have
chosen co-payment in your policy that
is between 10% to 50%, then any admissible
claim comes and the company approves the claim, the
claim will be shared in that.
You will have to pay the percentage of your co-payment
and the insurance company will pay the remaining amount.
Similarly,
you can also opt for Annual Aggregate Deductible,
where the minimum amount is ₹10,000 and the
maximum deductible amount
you can choose is ₹5 lakh.  Your policy coverage will start once this
deductible threshold limit is reached within the entire year.  The
next add-on is Claim Safeguard.  This
time the company has
covered all the non-medical items from all the four lists.  So,
you can cover the consumable items
in your policy through this add-on.
Apart from this, personal accident, which
also covers accidental death and permanent total disability,
is provided by the insurance company at different sums according to your four variants.  Personal accident cover of
₹10 lakh can be availed in the base variant i.e. Classic,
₹20 lakh in Select variant,
₹50 lakh in Elite variant and ₹1 crore in Black variant.  You
can also avail add-on of daily hospital cash.  That means, for the number of days the patient remains admitted,
apart from the treatment expenses,
some daily cash will also be given.  The lower two
variants are Classic and Select, here
you can claim ₹1000 per day.  And the
higher variant is Elite, in this ₹2000
per day and in the top variant Black,
₹4000 per day of daily hospital cash
can be claimed and the maximum number of days
limit is 30 days.  Apart from this,
you also get the add-on of Well Consult Plus in
which OPD expenses can be covered.
That is, if you want to cover diagnostic tests,
doctor's visit expenses, medicines, then
include the add-on of Well Consult Plus in your policy and these
OPD expenses will also be covered.  The percentage of the
sum insured amount of Total Well Consult OPD Benefit that
you can use for which expense is
visible on the screen right now.
If you go cashless, you
get the full claim amount but there may be
some co-payment on reimbursement.
Apart from Indian geographical limits, if you
want to get treatment outside India, then
for that also the company has provided two add-ons in Ratio 3.0 plan.  The
first one is
borderless, in which if
the diagnosis is done outside India and
you want to get the treatment done outside India, then its sum
insured will be according to your variant.
If you have the base variant
Classic then this add-on
is not available in it.  If you have the Select variant, you can claim up to
₹1 lakh, if you have the Elite variant, you can claim up to ₹50 lakh and if you have the
Black variant, you can claim up to ₹5 crore.  The
company has also offered the add-on of Borderless for Specific Diseases.  These
listed diseases have to be treated
outside India.  But
their diagnosis should be done in India.  So you can claim that too.
This add-on is not available in the base variant Classic.  You can avail borderless coverage for specific diseases up to
₹1 lakh in the Select variant,
₹50 lakh in the Elite variant and up to ₹5 crore in the top variant, the Black variant.
To make the premium of Borderless reasonable, the company has also given you the option of co-payment.  That
means, if
you want to share the claim during treatment,
you can also choose the co-payment option.
Now friends, here comes the most important part of the video
that we have understood all the coverage, benefits, add
ons etc.  Please tell me quickly
how much will this plan cost?  So for this
I have taken a standard family size of
two adults and two children.  The
age of adults is 38 and 35 years and the age of children is
12 years and 9 years.  His address is
Delhi and he does not have any pre-
existing disease.  For pricing,
I will tell you two premiums in each variant.  The
first premium will be for sum insured of ₹1 lakh
and the second premium will be
for unlimited sum insured so that you can
understand the difference in how much money the insurance company is charging for
converting sum insured from ₹10 lakh to unlimited sum insured.  The
only add-on I have added to these prices
is Claim Safeguard which
covers all the four lists of consumable items which I think is very
important.  It should be in your policy.
So first of all the classic variant which is the most base
variant which has many types of
cappings and submits.
You will get room rent only for the general ward.  So,
for a coverage of ₹1 lakh, this family will have to pay
₹22,243 annually
and if the same family takes unlimited sum insured
in the classic variant, then it becomes
₹29,289
annually.  At the same time, if this family
takes the variant above this, that is selected.  So,
for an annual sum insured of ₹1 lakh,
they will have to pay only ₹25,523.
And if they choose to upgrade it to
Unlimited Sum Insured, they will have to
pay ₹33,638 for the Select variant.
If you want to buy this Elite variant for ₹1 lakh,
you will have to pay ₹30,764
and for unlimited sum insured in Elite
variant, it becomes ₹38,244.
Now let's talk about the top variant i.e. Black.
This family will get coverage of ₹1 lakh
for ₹31,674 and if you want to take the top variant with unlimited sum
insured then it becomes ₹
44167.
If we talk about the membership of Neva Bupa One, then
its estimated cost is ₹6 to ₹7000.
But within that you get annual health
checkups.  Also, your
claims are addressed on priority.
Whatever concerns you have will be
attended to timely.  Actually,
this is the right of all policy holders.  But by
adding an annual health checkup feature, an attempt has been made to
create a loyal community with this membership.  Due to which the
retention rate of policy holders can also increase.
Now from the pricing you must have got an idea
whether the company is charging a reasonable price for it
or is charging a lot of money.  Let us
check this difference once again and see
how much extra money the company charged for insuring unlimited sum from ₹1 lakh.  If we
talk about the Classic variant, there
is a difference of approximately ₹7000 in which the
sum insured becomes unlimited.  Whereas
in Select Plan this difference becomes
₹8,000.  In the Elite variant, this difference
is ₹8,000 and in the Black variant,
this difference is ₹13,000.
Now this question may also be coming to your mind that we have
understood the variants but which of these
variants should we take?  Looking at the cappings and supplements that the company has put in the lower two
variants, Classic and Select,
I feel that you get good options from
them at a reasonable price compared to other companies.
But
if you want to go with the Reshore 3.0 plan,
then you can choose the sum insured as per your wish - Rs
5 lakh, Rs 10 lakh or
unlimited, but you should take the variant only - Alt or
Black.  Now let's talk about
Unlimited Sum Insured which
is the most highlighted feature of this plan.  I have two problems with the word '
Unlimited' in Unlimited Sum Insured.  First of all,
this is
an inviting word in unlimited health insurance itself that you
increase your claim expenses.  Suppose
my policy has unlimited sum
insured and for this I have paid ₹10 to
₹1,000 extra to the company.  So
after going to the hospital,
should I take average service or should I take top end
service?  Obviously, I
need the best and most expensive treatment.  So overall I increase the claim cost
due to which the
premiums will also increase in the future.  The second
problem with the unlimited term is
that hospitals will also be
very interested in increasing the claim cost.  Now, it is possible that
they may not be able to change the main line of treatment,
but the expenses related to the treatment,
such as tests,
medicines, and other services, may become expensive.
Excessive use of non-medical items
or recommending expensive tests or
unwanted tests
increases the overall claim cost for the company and
you may also have to bear the burden of out-of-pocket expenses.
Now you can understand this in the same way that we
go to a restaurant and order food by
looking at the menu.  So we
understand this very well.  First, we decide in 10 minutes what
each one should eat and try to ensure
that everyone is satisfied and
no food is wasted.  On the contrary, if we
go to a cave or a wedding
where there is
no limit on the food we can consume.  There is no limit on frequency,
so you see there
how much food is wasted.  That is just an example of marriage.  This
is an example of food.  So it does
n't make much difference to us.  But
whatever excess amount is spent here
for any treatment, the
company will not bear the burden from its pocket next year.  That is going to be
revised in our premiums.
So I think
defining a proper limit on sum insured is a good and
conservative way to control claim costs
and of course health insurance
companies will have complete data on what the average
claim is.  But still, somewhere
it motivates the policy holders and hospitals to
increase the claim cost.
And this burden will not fall on those who are
taking the claim.  This amount will have to be paid by those innocent
policy holders who do not make claims for five-five
years just to save their lock the
clock benefit.  The
burden of premium revision due to inflation will
definitely fall on you.  And one more thing I would
like to say is that I would not like to join such a plan, such a
risk pool, such a group in
which even the health insurance
company does not know what my maximum
liability is.  If a company has
sold a plan with sum insured of ₹1 lakh
and has sold 100 policies, does it know
what is its maximum liability?  But with unlimited sum insured
policies, how do you estimate the maximum number of
claims that could come in the next year
?  So the conclusion of my opinion on Reshore 3.0 is
that if you want to take a plan then you can
take the top two variants.  But
I don't think unlimited sum insured is
beneficial for the policy holders.  This
is definitely beneficial for the company which can collect premiums worth
lakhs and crores of rupees by showing such features.
But if we talk about sustainability and affordability,
this can become a problem for policy holders in the future.
What is your opinion about this plan?  What
is your opinion?  Please do let me know by commenting.
If you enjoyed this transparent and unbiased review of Ratio 3.0 today, please
like the video to show your love and support.
Please share this information wherever necessary.  If you want to receive similar
innovative and unbiased videos
related to insurance in the future, then do
not forget to subscribe to the channel.
In health insurance, you don't just pay the premium for the policy.
You also have some rights
which have been given to you by IRDA and not by the insurance company.
But their
benefits are there only when you have complete knowledge about them.
I have explained such top seven rights in this video.
You must watch this video
once.  I am Arvinder Singh, see you
in the next video.  Till then
take care, stay fit and stay healthy.  Jai
Hind.